Guide to the Records of the Asian/Pacific/American Institute RG.21.35
New York University Archives
- Series III: Events, 1995-2003
  - Subseries A: General (Alphabetical)
    - Asian Pacific American Youth Identity Forum: General, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Asian Pacific American Youth Identity Forum: Building Bridges, 1999; Folder Contains 1 mini DV. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Asian Pacific American Youth Identity Forum: Exploring the Unseen and Unspoken, 2000; Folder includes 2 mini DVs. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Asian Pacific American Youth Identity Forum: Freezone, 2000; Folder includes 10 mini DVs and 13 cassette tapes. (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Asian Pacific American Youth Identity Forum: Pursuit of Pop, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Asian Pacific American Youth Identity Forum: Urbanizasian, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Asians in America Conference, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Asians in America Conference, 1996; Folder includes 1 VHS tape (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Asians in America Conference, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      Separated Materials note
      Poster moved to box 14.
    - Asians in America Conference, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Assumed Identity by Susan Sponsler, 2000; Folder includes 1 mini DV. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Benefit Reading for Premonitions: The Kaya Anthology of New Asian North American Poetry, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Book Series: Greg Robinson, By Order of the President: FDR and the Internment of Japanese Americans, 2002; Folder consists of 1 mini DV (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Breaking Stereotypes: Asian Pacific American Musicians, 2003; Folder includes 2 DVs and 1 VHS tape. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Brown Bag Lunch Series: Gary Okihiro On the Death of Ethnic Studies, 2003; Folder includes 2 mini DVs. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Brown Bag Lunch Series: May Joseph, Migrancy, Citizenship and New York City, 2003; Folder consists of 3 mini DVs (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Brown Bag Lunch Series: Reclaiming Lives with Ruthanne Lum McCunn, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Brown Bag Lunch Series: Re-visioning the City, 2003; Folder consists of 1 VHS tape. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Carved in Silence Question and Answer Session, 2002; Folder consists of 1 mini DV (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Chang-Rae Lee Reading A Gesture Life, 2000; Folder includes 1 VHS tape and 1 mini DV. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Civil Rights Issues and Post 9-11 Law Enforcement/Community Relations in New York: A Fact Finding Forum, 2003; Folder includes 9 mini DVs, 1 VHS tape, and 7 cassette tapes. (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Coming of Age in Amelika, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Coming to Terms: The Impact of WWII on American Jews and Japanese Americans Today, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Commencement and Alumni Receptions, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Community Health and the Trauma of Immigration, 2003; Folder consists of 5 DVs. (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Course Offerings, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Course Offerings, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Course Offerings, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Course Offerings, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Course Offerings, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Dana Tai Soon Burgess: Reflections in Motion Performance, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Defining Communities of Interest, 2000; Folder consists of 9 cassette tapes. (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Dilemmas of Historical Memory: Locating South Asian Americans in Asian America Lecture, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Dog Eat Dog Party with Jessica Hagedorn, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Dogeaters: Conversation with Jessica Hagedorn, 2001; Folder includes 2 mini Dvs and 2 VHS tapes (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - East of California Conference, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Effective Clinical Practice with Asian Americans Symposium, 2000; Folder includes 10 mini DV. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Elegant Chaos: Jessica Hagedorn and Guillermo Gomez-Pena, 1999; 3 mini Dvs (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Emerging Artists Series: Le Thi Diem Thuy, 1999; Folder includes 2 mini DVs. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Emerging Artists Series: Staceyann Chin, "I was Born with Two Tongues", 1999; Folder includes 2 VHS tapes. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Emerging Artists Series: Suheir Hammad, 2001; Folder includes 1 mini DV (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Emerging Artists Series: Vijay Iyer, 2000; Folder includes 2 cassette tapes. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Empire of Care Book Launch with Catherine Ceniza Choy, 2003; Folder includes 1 DV. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Events Calendar, 2000-2001 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Events Calendar, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Events Calendar, 2002; Folder consists of 1 VHS tape. (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Events Calendar, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Events Calendar, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Events Calendar and Pan-A-Visions (A/P/A Studies Newsletter), 1998 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Film Screening: First Person Plural, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Film Screening: The Game of Their Lives, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Film Screening: Raising Our Voices, 2002; Folder consists of 1 DAT. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Film Screening: Say I Do, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Film Screening: An Untold Triumph, 2003; Folder includes 1 DV. (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Flower Drum Song: Over the Decades, 2002; Folder includes 3 VHS tapes and 2 DV cams. (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Garden of Export Delights with Swati Khurana, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Gender, Cultural Citizenship and the Nation Symposium, 2002; Folder consists of one poster. (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Gender, Cultural Citizenship and Transnationalism, 2002; Folder consists of 5 mini DVs, 4 cassette tapes, and 2 VHS tapes. (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Helen Zia: Asian American Dreams Book Reception, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - I of Beholder exhibition curated by Judy Kim, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Illiterate Heart by Meena Alexander, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - In the Country of my Imagination, 2002; Folder includes 9 mini DVs and 5 cassettes. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Indonesia Conference, 1998; Folder consists 6 mini DVs, 4 cassettes, and 3 VHS. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Is Charlie Chan Really Dead?: Asians in America Conference, 1999; Folder Contains 5 Hi8. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Maya Lin and Michael Brenson Dialog, 1998; Folder contains 2 mini DVs and 2 VHS tapes. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Maya Lin at the A/P/A Gallery, Undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Meet the Artist: Jaishri Abichandani, 2002; Folder consists of 1 VHS tape. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Meet the Artist: Ong Keng Sen, 2002; Folder consists on 1 mini DV. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Mind's Desire by Jaishri Abichandani, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Momotaro/ Peach Boy: New Works by Tomie Arai, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - My Country Versus Me Book Launch, 2002; Folder includes 1 DVcam and 1 VHS tape. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - New York Before Chinatown Book Party, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Nori Morimoto Exhibit, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Open House Reception, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Pacific Islands, Atlantic Worlds Symposium, 2001; Folder includes 17 mini DVs. (Box 11, Folder 14)
      General note
      From container list: All mini DVs are on loan to Alexandra Chang, Event Coordinator A/P/A Institute, who will return them Fall 2007.
    - Palates of Pleasure: The Philosophy and Politics of Southeast Asian Food Symposium, 2001; Folder includes 28 mini DVs. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - A Photographic Journey with Corky Lee, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Please Do Not Throw Peanuts at My God: Installation by Siddhartha Joag, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Professional Workshop: Skills for Working in a Multicultural America, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Program and Institute Brochure, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Public Displays of Asianness- A Conference on Asian American Popular Culture, 1998; Folder contains 3 mini DVs and 9 cassettes. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Race and Social Injustice: The Diallo Verdict Panel Discussion, 2000; Folder consists of 3 mini DVs. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Resident Aliens Art Installation by Siddhartha Joag and Tomie Arai, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Rethinking Ethnic and Area Studies Conference, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Rethinking New York City: A Post 9-11 Roundtable, 2002; Folder includes 1 VHS tape and 3 mini DVs. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Serene Ford Northington: Getting in the Picture, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Serene Ford Northington: War Retold, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Sia Figel Reading They Who Do Not Grieve, 2000; Folder consists of 1 VHS tape. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - South Asian Studies Speaker Series, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - South Asian Studies Speaker Series Leadership Training: Part I, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - South Asian Studies Speaker Series Leadership Training: Part II, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Student Open House, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Student Open House, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Tamiment Library Reception Celebrating First A/P/A Collection at NYU, 2003; Folder includes 1 cassette tape. (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Trinh T. Minh-Ha Lecture, 2001; Folder consists of 1 cassette tape. (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Two Men, Two Cameras, Different Perspectives: Corky Lee and Mel Rosenthal, 2002; Folder consists of 1 VHS tape. (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Undesirable Elements by Ping Chong, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Vestiges of War Conference, 1999; Folder contains 17 mini Dvs (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Vestiges of War Conference, 2002; Folder includes 1 mini DV. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Where is Home? Conference, 1997; Folder includes 29 cassette tapes. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Who's Next- North Korea and Beyond, 2003; Folder includes 2 VHS tapes, 2 DVRs, 2 cassette tapes, and 2 DV cams. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Wilfredo Lam and the International Avant Garde, 2002; Folder consists of 2 mini DVs. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - You Are Being Watched: INS Special Registration and the War on Terrorism, 2003; Folder includes 3 mini DVs and 1 VHS tape. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Youth Forum Meetings, 2000; 4 mini DVs and 1 VHS tape. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Subseries B: Posters
    - Asians in America Conference Banner, 1998; Large Nylon Banner (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Asians in America Conference Poster, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      Removed from box 8, folder 4.
    - Dana Tai Soon Burgess: Reflections in Motion Poster, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      Five copies
      Removed from box 10, folder 11.
    - East of California Conference Poster, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      Removed from box 8, folder 9.
      Seven copies
    - Palates of Pleasure- The Philosophy and Politics of Southeast Asian Food Poster, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      Removed from box 11, folder 6.
    - Public Displays of Asianness- A Conference on Asian American Popular Culture Poster, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      Removed from box 9, folder 1.
      Six copies
    - Vestiges of War- The Philippine-American War and Its Aftermath Poster, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      Removed from box 9, folder 3.
    - Where is Home? Conference Poster, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      Removed from box 8, folder 8.
  - Subseries C: General (Chronological)
    - I of Beholder Exhibit, 0200-2000 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Assumed Identity Exhibit, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Garden of Export Delights Exhibit, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Coming of Age in Amelika Exhibit, 2001-2002 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Spring/Summer 2002 Calendar of Events (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Please Do Not Throw Peanuts at My God Exhbit, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Mind's Desire, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Fall Course Listing, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Fall Calendar of Events, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - A Photographic Journey with Corky Lee, 2002-2003 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Flower Drum Song: Over the Decades, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Spring Course Listing, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Spring Calendar of Events, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - War Retold: Photographs of Vietnam Exhibit, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - An Untold Triumph-Film Screening: Filipino American Soldiers of World War II, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Resident Aliens Exhibit, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Fall Calendar of Events, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Fall Artist-in-Residence: Fay Chiang, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Fresh Talk Revisited: New York Artists from Fresh Talk/Daring Gazes Exhibit, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - NYU Community of Color Reception, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Through Windows: One woman performance by Susana Lei'ataua, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Brown Bag Lunch Series: Professor Thuy Linh Tu, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Film Screening: Asian Americans and 9/11, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Screening and Panel Discussion: Matters of Race: The Changing Face of America, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - From Internment and Detention: Abuses Under the Threat of War-Civil Rights Lecture with Dale Minami, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - A/P/A Studies Gallery Exhibition Opening - Fresh Talk Revisited: New York Artists from Fresh Talk/Daring Gazes, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Two Bells, Two Worlds: Film Screening and Discussion, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - A/P/A Studies Gallery Artists Talk - Fresh Talk Revisited: New York Artists from Fresh Talk/Daring Gazes, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - A/P/A Studies 2004 Artist-In-Residence Kickoff Celebration, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Bustin' Through Hollywood: Blue Crush, Bend It Like Beckham, & Better Luck Tomorrow, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Pan Asian Dialogue: Queer Asian/Pacific American Activism, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Brown Bag Lunch Series with Jasbir Puar, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Chris' Birthday Jam!, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Dissertation Series - Choreographing Chineseness: Global Citiies and the Performance of Ethnicity, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Jessica Hagedorn's Dream Jungle: Book Series Launch & Discussion, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Brown Bag Lunch Series with May Joseph, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Community Health Forum - Walking the Bicultural Tightrope: Psychoanalytic and Literary Perspectives on the New American, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - Annual Holiday Party, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - Spring Course Listings, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - Spring Calendar of Events, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - My Life in Progress by Ian Kim (Student Exhibition), 2004 (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - My Life in Progress by Ian Kim (Student Exhibition Opening), 2004 (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - Activist Media: Celebrating 35 Years of Independent Film & Video with Third World Newsreel, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - Impossible Subjects: Illegal Aliens and the Making of Modern America, 1924-1965 (Book Launch & Discussion with Mae Ngai), 2004 (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - Share & Tell An A/P/A Student Conference, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 45)
    - Lecture & Slide Show Presentation with Anthony W. Lee: "When the Cobbling Began: Photography and Chinese Shoemakers in a 19th Century New England Factory Town", 2004 (Box 16, Folder 46)
    - Artist Talk with Ian Kim, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 47)
    - Brown Bag Lunch Series with Jamie Lew, Ph.D.: "Schooling Success and Failure of Korean American Youth in Urban Schools - Significance of Class, Race, & School Context", 2004 (Box 16, Folder 48)
    - Book Launch & Discussion with Graham Russell Gao Hodges: Anna May Wong: From Laundryman's Daughter to Hollywood Legend, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 49)
    - Queer Asian Pacific Legacy: A Regional Queer Asian/Pacific American Conference, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 50)
    - Disseration Series with Svati Shah, Ph.D. Candidate at Columbia University: "Solicitation, Migration and Daily Wage Labor: Gender, Sexuality and Negotiating Work in an Indian City", 2004 (Box 16, Folder 51)
    - 11th Annual Forum on Asian/Pacific American Youth Culture (APAYA), 2004 (Box 16, Folder 52)
    - A Most Unlikely Hero: A Documentary on the Fight for Racial Equality in the Marine Corps, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 53)
    - Suburban Sahibs: Three Immigrant Families and Their Passage from India to America (Book Launch & Discussion with S. Mitra Kalita), 2004 (Box 16, Folder 54)
    - Different Generations/Same Issues: An Evening of Performances Arranged by Fay Chiang, A/P/A Studies Artist-in-Residence, 2003-2004 (Box 16, Folder 55)
    - Brown Bag Lunch Series with Lok Siu, Ph.D.: Diasporic Citizenships: Politics of Belonging for Chinese in Panama, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 56)
    - At Home in the World: Fictions and Literatures of Asian America and Beyond, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 57)
    - A/P/A Studies Conference audio tapes 1-3 of 3, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 58)
    - Fictions of Asian Americans 1-3 of 3, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 59)
    - Java House: An Evening of Asian American Performance, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 60)
    - caucASIANS: Asian Adoptees in White Families: A Discussion on the Transracial Adoption Paradox, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 61)
    - University Commencement Reception, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 62)
    - A Dialogue with Seperation: Picturing an American Chinatown 1990-2002 Exhibit, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 63)
    - Asian Women United Reunion, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 64)
- Series IV: Photographs
  - Photographs: A/P/A Events and Activities, undated (Box 15)